okay here is uh session four of
operation get strong and
sexy this was a very very good session
best session yet uh so we start off with
back squats here is Aaron this is um
this 105
lbs she gets five
reps um actually I think she gets four
reps on this one but she's going rock by
there that is very deep as to Grass
there keeps perfect uh lumbar position
when she does that okay here's Sammy
this is 145 I don't mind her not quite
reaching parallel just because I know
she can in
competition I just want her to try to
focus on keeping a good Arch Her Butt
Wink is getting better there's me off in
the background watching from the side
view um so I'm happy cuz her her she's
keeping better lumbar position okay here
is Aaron I told her not to go quite as
deep uh this time to get five reps she
stops she goes a little past parallel
but it's a lot easier this Set uh than I
told her to go deeper there she's uh as
she gains experience she'll get better
with learning
exactly where to stop uh I don't want
quite as to Grass I want her just a
little above but I want her to get
comfortable going going below below
parallel uh cuz she feels strong there
in powerlifting you just have to reach a
thigh parallel position with the ground
like Sammy right here um if I pause I'll
show you
um um if I pause at the bottom of our
sets I'll do it next time I hit the
wrong pause button
um here's Aaron uh this set I really
like I think she goes the right depth
um you see she's
about like that there is well below
parallel
um and uh she so she ends up
uh she got a set of four and two sets of
five with 105 lbs two weeks ago that was
her one rep max so she's kicking butt
um here's
Sammy this uh this looks like parallel
it might be a little bit High either way
in competition I'll I'll have her go a
little deeper she'll nail it but I
wanted to see uh last week she got 135
for three sets of five so I bumped it up
to 145 and she got three sets of five
and her lumbar position improved
so um I was very happy with Samy squat
performance today
um now I just for the fun of it wanted
to see if Aaron could uh could hit a new
PR just to give her some good confidence
this is uh the most she's done and she
got two two actually she got three but
she stops at parallel this is 125 or
maybe 120 I think it's 120 not sure uh
so that's the most weight she's ever
done uh but she did skimp a little bit
on range of motion I think I made her go
deeper the next set here's uh Sammy with
uh
185 uh this is looks it says a little
bit high but this is uh 185 that's the
most she's
done and uh just such a good strong
squatter keep in mind this is the second
week of them so here's Aaron this is 120
again and you can tell she's going well
below
parallel um and look at this knee
position this is what I'm so happy about
see the knees they stay they don't come
in too much that's the knee that has
problems and so her vus collapse is
getting better with M and everyone can
can learn good knee control when going
light and doing just body weight but
when you go heavy it's harder here's
Sammy again just had her get one rep
with 185 again want them getting
familiar with heavier weights because
they don't have a lot of time to prepare
for the competition it's it's five weeks
out okay here's Aaron conventional
deadlifts um this is 140 lbs so we
bumped it Up 5 lbs last week she got
three sets of five with
135 I just want to keep bumping them
bumper up 5 lbs per week great form this
is Sammy this is 205 now
uh Sammy is a uh and I recognize this so
well because this is how I lift see she
wants to round a little bit here and
keep her hips really high and so I
recognize this very well because I lift
the same way as
her so I would like her ideally to get
uh when she sets up to drop the hips
just slightly bend the knees a little
more and get the chest up more but uh
I'm all right with her pulling like the
at the the end of the day she can pull
this way a lot of people a lot of
strength coaches would say oh my God
that's so dangerous it's not Sammy can
lift like this just fine
she won't she won't hurt herself uh and
this is the way she feels strongest um
here's Aaron again with 140 busts out
five reps easy this is very very
symmetrical uh she's great form I'm very
happy with her her deadlift form
um Sammy again
uh again this is pretty good position
right here if she just had a little more
low back Arch but again some people with
very strong glutes like Samy's glutes
are so strong the glutes actually
activate higher when in slight post your
tilt compared to when you have a very
strict Arch and to your tilt and I think
that's why Samy does it but uh as you
can tell Samy's a hip dominant person
she wants to lift with all hips but I'm
okay with this uh I'm very happy with
her strength this is 205 she's getting
five reps pretty
easily and uh I'm
just she keeps going up and up and wait
last week we used
185 okay uh here's Aaron's last set of
140 for
deadlifts beautiful form she's a natural
deadlifter one thing with Aaron I do
tell her is right when she gets right
there right past the knees I tell her
think glutes think of a hip thrust think
of pushing your hips
forward uh and keeping the bar closer to
her body sometimes she wants to bring it
out and when she focuses on keeping it
close to her body skimming her thighs
she does better
um I think Aaron got six reps with the
last
set and then here's Sam
again with 205 or last set of
deadlift
uh looks like a piece of cake for one
thing about Sammy
her her form looks a bit different each
rep and each set it's she's and you can
tell she's got room for improvement
because of this but she's such a strong
lifter that she can get away with it so
she gains experience and learns how to
set up tighter and she'll get even
better um her hands hurt really bad when
she do this cuz these bars are very
knurled uh that'll go away in time okay
here's Aaron with the bench press this
is
70 70 lb
um and uh very happy with Aaron's form
here on the bench here's Sammy 85lb
bench
press happy with her form
here um except that one she hit the bar
she lined up too
close um Aaron again with uh now I don't
like them scooting in the middle of the
set
there both of them will get better
better at uh learning how to set up at
the proper
distance but very good form very good
position here with
Aaron
um same again 85 lbs again she's very I
want her lowering it right there right
uh um little bit lower on the chest she
wants to lower it up
high uh Aaron's lowering it into good
position right
there and and uh and Aaron's keeping
good arm position here if you can see
right there the the arm angle is good
lowered a little bit too high there but
you got to be impressed this this is
their second week of doing bench press
this
way and uh form is looking real good so
um
in there she sunk it into her chest a
little bit which this is actually legal
a lot of lifters are doing this now on
powerlifting kind of sinking it into
their chest there Sammy lowers it into
good position there
okay there she laughs and lets out her
air that's not good and then uh but ends
up getting three sets of three I believe
with 85 okay now we move on to the hip
thrust uh I wanted them to do High Reps
here and I tell told Aaron to go faster
this works the glutes when you do High
Reps like this it's good for glutes uh
it burns like crazy this constant
tension she doesn't touch the ground
with the bar what I like see Aaron
vertical tibas right here I like to see
straight up and down with the tibia The
Shins pushing through the
heels uh and she gets 20 reps holds it
for a count of 10 um very good form
here's Sammy with
and uh Sammy busts out 20 reps
here with
185 fast reps uh uh and sami's in good
position here vertical shins so she's
the right distance she's hinging at the
back she's not sliding back too much
which she tends to do every once in a
while and Sammy sometimes lines up with
her feet too close here which she did
not here so this was a great set from
Sammy she locks it out very high into
full hip extension okay and now here's
Aaron with 155 she has never done this
for 20 reps
before um great form
uh I
think she wants to stop at 15ish and
then I made her do
20 yeah she's maybe skimping a little
bit there but
still uh when she holds it I'd like to
see her a little more in complete hip
extension she's sagging just a little
bit but this is still working her glutes
very much so and so this is a PR for
Aaron with 155 for 20 a 20 rep PR she's
never done 20 reps 155
and now this is Sammy this is 225 I told
her to get as many reps as you
can
um she's a little wobbly
here I don't know how many she got maybe
like 12 or so now she's just being weird
having weird reps but anyway this is
still good form uh on the lockout one
thing I like is Samy's really good at
her
lockout um moved on to some band seated
hip abduction
options um High rep we like 20 reps with
these uh but we just like the this is
very awkward to be filmed with the this
exercise we say you don't make o there's
Mikey getting stretching his hips out um
hold it but try to hold the last uh the
last rep of the set for like 10 seconds
five to 10 seconds get that extra
squeeze
Sammy now Sammy didn't feel them on this
set the last workout she was feeling
them big time and then on this one she
didn't and it's probably has to do with
her
position uh like people to toy around
with SE Shin angle is going that way
sometimes people like their feet a
little closer to their butt sometimes
people like vertical
shins uh some people like their feet a
little closer but it's kind of weird
because sometimes Sammy feels these a
ton and her glutes are burning and
sometimes she doesn't
um here's Aon doing another set and
these are a very important part of the
glute building program for powerlifting
is this that important no but we're
trying to build glutes also and so these
little things help the high rep sets of
band seated hip abductions the high rep
sets of hip thrust they help a
ton nearly every girl I've ever trained
saw huge results once doing this in the
glutes even if they were
powerlifting uh powerlifting does not
build the best glutes doing this stuff
does
um and
uh we're so we're doing a powerlifting
program but I'm making sure to also
build the best glutes as possible and
Sammy and Aaron are both already
starting to see results in their glutes
so on this set we um see this we start
in a valgus position more so have a
little bit wider stance and then
out more um but Sammy wasn't feeling
that much either so it's just kind of
weird with Sammy sometimes hit or miss
with this exercise cuz last week there
was the first session of the week she
was totally filling her glutes this
session not so much
so okay and then I tried teaching them
uh chess supported dumbbell
Rose um so here's Sammy with uh this is
25 lbs I would like to see see this
forearm angle I would like to see the
forearms being vertical here um but this
is sami's first time doing this I didn't
want to say too much but uh Sammy using
uh I think these are 25 Pounders here's
20 lbs for Aaron this looked very easy
for her aon's form looks a little bit
better uh as you can see her Shin or
forearms are a little bit
more verticalist I don't want I don't
mind a little bit of angle but I don't
want to see them completely bent like
this I'd like to see straight
down but uh focus on really squeezing
the back muscles together um so I like
this exercise for this purpose and
here's Sammy again um this is good
form now it is tough
for women to do these because this bench
is as wide as them so this the dumbbells
kind of Hit the bench for guys it's
easier cuz we're wider and the dumbbells
don't
hit
uh I don't care Sammy wanted to put her
knees up on that set no big deal uh and
now here Aaron moves up in
weight
um still uses good form so
uh like throwing in some extra upper
back
exercises that's it